<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_governance">
 <title>Governance</title>
 <shortdesc> Information governance is about controlling an organization’s data. </shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>The data may be sensitive; or perhaps it is important that the data be absolutely accurate; or
   perhaps the organization must achieve legislative and compliance targets. Data governance
   includes the process and policies around the protection, curation, and access to data and
   encompasses all of privacy protection, data security, and data audit.</p>
  <p>Information governance is about controlling an organization’s data. The data may be sensitive;
   or perhaps it is important that the data be absolutely accurate; or perhaps the organization must
   achieve legislative and compliance targets. Data governance includes the process and policies
   around the protection, curation, and access to data. Data governance encompasses all of privacy
   protection, data security, and data audit. </p>
  <p>PHEMI Central helps organizations achieve compliance objectives by providing an
   industry-pioneering set of capabilities to manage the privacy, security, and governance of data.
   These capabilities are fully configurable and are automatically enforced throughout the data
   lifecycle.</p>
  <p>A governance policy is a coordinated approach to protecting data and assigning privileges to
   users. To control and protect your data, your organization should have a clearly defined policy
   governing data.</p>
  <p><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> enforces governance policies for privacy and
   security within the data warehouse, rather than at the application layer. In-system governance
   ensures that data custodians, not application developers, retain control over privacy and
   security. Managing privacy and security within the data store also simplifies application
   development and the use of analytics tools.</p>
  <p/>
 </conbody>
</concept>
