<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_privacy">
 <title>Privacy</title>
 <shortdesc>Privacy is restricting information access to those who have the right to access it. </shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>'s innovative Privacy by Design framework was
   designed from the ground up to define, manage, and enforce data sharing agreements and privacy
   policies. </p>
  <ul id="ul_if1_npb_dr">
   <li>
    <p><b>Attribute-based access control</b>—Users are tagged with attributes that describe their
     level of authorization. Data is tagged with attributes that describe its visibility. These two
     attributes can be used in access policies that are applied to data collections and datasets to
     enforce rightful access privileges. For example, a data analyst with Level 1 clearance might be
     able to export fully identified data, an analyst with Level 2 clearance might only have access
     to de-identified data. Attribute based access control reduces complexity and reduces the risk
     of data breach. Also, an attributed-based approach to privacy is helpful when not all uses or
     access requirements for data are understood up-front, or when new types of data are frequently
     introduced into the system—both common scenarios in health care, for example. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Selective data tagging</b>—Configured attribute-based access can be enriched and extended
     with context-specific protections by using the Data Processing Function framework to extract
     and re-tag information. For example, a Social Security or Social Insurance Number extracted
     from a health scan generally marked confidential can be selectively retagged as personally
     identifiable.</p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Automatic anonymization and de-identification</b>—<ph
      conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> can be set to automatically invoke a Data Processing
     Function that can de-identify, encrypt, redact, or mask any data element. A DPF can even
     include sophisticated data dependency algorithms to reduce the risk of re-identification. A <ph
      conkeyref="product-vars/admin"/> can also construct datasets that strip out identifying data
     elements. Centralizing anonymization and de-identification helps reduce data sprawl and reduces
     the risk of data consistency errors. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>End to end access policy enforcement</b>—Every query for data to <ph
      conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> is mediated by the PHEMI Policy Enforcement Engine,
     which compares the request against the privacy protections that have been placed on the data.
     At no time can users, applications, or external systems bypass the Policy Enforcement Engine to
     access data directly. </p>
   </li>
  </ul>
 </conbody>
</concept>
