<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_abac">
 <title>Attribute-Based Access Control</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p>specify protections for cell-level security control?</p>
  <p>The PHEMI Central DPF system enables the tagging of derived data elements with privacy
   protections. Available privacy protections are configured in the PHEMI Management Console by an
   Administrator, and are then available for DPFs to tag data with context specific protections. For
   instance, the SSN extracted from a health record object may be tagged as CONFIDENTIAL. </p>
  <p>Privacy tags (called Data Attributes in PHEMI Central) can then be combined with rules around
   user properties (such as Doctor or Analyst) to control access to data of a specific sensitivity.
   For instance, an Administrator may create a rules (called an Access Policy) that grants READ
   access to user's that are Doctors for data that is CONFIDENTIAL. They can then attach this Access
   Policy to a set of data, such as a collection of health records. </p>
  <p>This approach to data protection is called Attribute Based Access Control (ABAC) and is a more
   general version of the more commonly used Role Based Access Control (RBAC). An ABAC approach is
   advantageous when not all uses/access controls around data are known up front and when new types
   of data may be introduced into the system -- both common scenarios in healthcare, where data
   evolves and changes as well as the allowed use of data. </p>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p>Attribute Based Access Control Users can be tagged with attributes that describe their level of
   authorization. Data can be tagged with attributes that describe its level of sensitivity or its
   requirements for privacy. Together, these two attributes can be combined to allow sophisticated
   access privileges to identified, unidentifiable, deidentified, or anonymized data.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
 </conbody>
</concept>
