<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_governance-policies">
 <title>Governance Policies</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p>To protect your data and the privacy of your data, you should have your organization's
   governance policy in place before configuring the PHEMI system. A governance policy is a
   coordinated approach to protecting data and assigning privileges to users. </p>
  <p>There are three main aspects to a governance policy:</p>
  <ul id="ul_rh2_mxq_kq">
   <li><keyword>Data visibility</keyword>. Data can have different levels of visibility or
    sensitivity, and your organization may need to protect different data in different ways. You may
    want some data visible to every user but other data visible only to selected users. In the PHEMI
    system, these levels are called "data visibilities." <xref
     href="../Data_Visibilities/con_data-visibilities.xml#concept_data-visibilities">Tell me more
     about data visibilities</xref></li>
   <li><keyword>User authorizations</keyword>. Different users may be required to interact with data
    differently. For example, clinicians might be allowed to access all data, while researchers
    might be allowed to read only non-identified or de-identified data. <xref
     href="../Users/con_user-authorizations.xml">Tell me more about user authorizations</xref></li>
   <li><keyword>Access policies</keyword>. Your organization's governance policy will state how
    users with different authorizations can interact with data of different visibility. <xref
     href="../Access_Policies/con_access-policies.xml">Tell me more about access
    policies</xref></li>
  </ul>
  <p>The data visibilities, user authorizations, and access policies defined in your governance
   policies will drive how you configure the PHEMI system. If you are uncertain as to the
   appropriate data visibilities, user authorizations, or access policies to define for your
   organization, consult with your Information Officer, Privacy Officer, or with someone in a
   comparable role.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
