<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_privacy">
 <title>Privacy</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p/>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p><b>specify protections for cell-level security control?</b></p>
  <p>The PHEMI Central DPF system enables the tagging of derived data elements with privacy
   protections. Available privacy protections are configured in the PHEMI Management Console by an
   Administrator, and are then available for DPFs to tag data with context specific protections. For
   instance, the SSN extracted from a health record object may be tagged as CONFIDENTIAL. </p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>Privacy tags (called Data Attributes in PHEMI Central) can then be combined with rules around
   user properties (such as Doctor or Analyst) to control access to data of a specific sensitivity.
   For instance, an Administrator may create a rules (called an Access Policy) that grants READ
   access to user's that are Doctors for data that is CONFIDENTIAL. They can then attach this Access
   Policy to a set of data, such as a collection of health records. </p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>This approach to data protection is called Attribute Based Access Control (ABAC) and is a more
   general version of the more commonly used Role Based Access Control (RBAC). An ABAC approach is
   advantageous when not all uses/access controls around data are known up front and when new types
   of data may be introduced into the system -- both common scenarios in healthcare, where data
   evolves and changes as well as the allowed use of data.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
  <p>Privacy by Design PHEMI Central was built from the ground up on an innovative Privacy by Design
   framework to define, manage, and enforce data sharing agreements and privacy policies. Because
   PHEMI Central’s privacy, security, and governance features are one coordinated design across the
   system, you don’t have to rely on a cobbled-together mish-mash of security mechanisms to protect
   your organization’s sensitive data.</p>
  <p>Anonymization and De-Identification PHEMI Central can automatically de-identify, encrypt, or
   mask personal information and enforce privacy based on sophisticated user access privileges and
   fine-grained sharing and consent rules. PHEMI Central stores the fully identified data but
   strictly controls the rightful use of all digital assets. When the user’s access privileges and
   the recorded data sharing agreements dictate, PHEMI Central can invoke a data processing function
   to de-identify or anonymize any</p>
  <p>information information. Anonymization and de-identification may include disallowing access to
   personally identifiable information, masking certain information, redacting content, or may
   involve more sophisticated data dependency algorithms to reduce the risk of re-identification.
   Centralizing anonymization and de-identification helps reduce data sprawl and reduces the risk of
   data consistency errors.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
