<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_privacy">
 <title>Privacy</title>
 <shortdesc>Privacy is restricting information access to those who have the right to access it. </shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>'s Privacy by Design framework was designed from the
      ground up to define, manage, and enforce data-sharing agreements and privacy policies. This
      framework includes the following mechanisms:</p>
  <ul id="ul_if1_npb_dr">
   <li>
    <p><b>Attribute based access control (ABAC)</b>—Users are tagged with attributes that describe
          their authorizations to access data. Data is tagged with attributes that describe what its
          visibility should be. These two attributes are used in access policies that are applied to
          data collections and datasets to enforce rightful access privileges. For example, a data
          analyst with CONFIDENTIAL authorization might be able to export fully identified data,
          while an analyst with RESEARCHER authorization might only have access to de-identified
          data. </p>
        <p>Attribute based access control reduces complexity and reduces the risk of data breach. An
          attributed based approach to privacy is also especially helpful when not all uses or
          access requirements for data are understood up-front, or when new types of data are
          frequently introduced into the system (both common scenarios in health care, for example). </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Selective data tagging</b>—The attribute-based access configured in the system can be
          enriched and expanded with context-specific protections by using the Data Processing
          Function framework to extract and re-tag information. For example, scans of patient
          reports can be recognized and extracted by a DPF and fields selectively marked as PII
          (personally identifying information, as in a Social Security or Social Insurance Number)
          or NON_IDENTIFYING (as in a blood glucose measurement).</p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Automatic anonymization and de-identification</b>—<ph
            conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> can be set to automatically invoke a Data
          Processing Function that can de-identify, encrypt, redact, or mask any data element. A DPF
          can even include sophisticated data dependency algorithms to reduce the risk of
          re-identification. </p>
        <p>A <ph conkeyref="product-vars/admin"/> can also construct datasets that strip out
          identifying data elements. Centralizing anonymization and de-identification helps reduce
          data sprawl and reduces the risk of data consistency errors. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>End-to-end access policy enforcement</b>—Every query for data to <ph
            conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> is mediated by the PHEMI Policy Enforcement
          Engine, which compares the access request aginst the privacy protections that have been
          placed on the data. At no time can users, applications, or external systems bypass the
          Policy Enforcement Engine to access data directly. </p>
   </li>
  </ul>
 </conbody>
</concept>
