<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_define-governance-policy">
    <title>Define a Governance Policy</title>
    <shortdesc>Make sure your organization's governance policy is defined before you begin
        configuration.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>Your governance policy will drive how you configure  <ph
                    conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. Therefore, before configuring <ph
                    conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, you should make sure you have your
                organization's governance policy available to you. If you are uncertain as to the
                appropriate data visibilities, user authorizations, or access policies to define for
                your organization, consult with your Information Officer, Privacy Officer, or with
                someone in a comparable role.</p>
            <p>To define your organization's governance policy:</p>
        </context>
        <steps id="steps_dyv_y3c_3r">
            <step>
                <cmd>Identify the different sensitivity levels of the data you will be storing in
                        <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>You'll configure these as data visibilities. Data visibilities are attributes
                        used to tag ingested data for purposes of privacy and access control.
                        Examples of data visibilities are "CONFIDENTIAL," "SECRET," and "PII"
                        (Personally Identifiable Information).</p>
                    <p><xref
                            href="../data_visibilities/con_data-visibilities.xml#concept_data-visibilities"
                            >Tell me about data visibilities.</xref></p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Identify what authorizations your organization assigns to different users to
                    allow them to access data. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>Your user authorizations should reflect the actual permissions your personnel
                        are granted to interact with data with different visibility. </p>
                    <p><xref href="../users/con_user-authorizations.xml#concept_user-authorizations"
                            >Tell me about user authorizations.</xref></p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Specify the allowed combinations of user authorizations and data
                    visibilities.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>For example, a user with C_LEVEL authorization (perhaps a CEO, CIO, COO, or
                        CTO) might be permitted to access CONFIDENTIAL data, a user with RESEARCH
                        authorization might only be permitted to access only DE-IDENTIFIED data, and
                        a user with DOCTOR authorization might be allowed to see data of all
                        sensitivity. You'll capture these combinations as access policies.</p>
                    <p><xref
                            href="../access_policies/con_access-policies.xml#concept_access-policies"
                            >Tell me about access policies.</xref></p>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
