<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_define-governance-policy">
    <title>Defining a Governance Policy</title>
    <shortdesc/>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
            <p/>
            <p>1a. Identify the different visibilities (i.e. sensitivities) of data you will store
                and want to assign protections to. This is a key part of the Information Governance
                process. Consult your Information Officer or comparable position. Some examples of
                data visibilities are: </p>
            <p>- PII = Personally Identifiable Information</p>
            <p>- NonPII = Non Personally Identifiable Information</p>
            <p>- CONFIDENTIAL = Data with that is sensitive and requires a certain level of access
                (or certification) on the users part.</p>
            <p>- SECRET = An increase in sensitivity beyond CONFIDENTIAL.</p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>1b. Identify the different authorizations that users may have in order to gain access
                to data. This should be done in concert with (1a) where data visibilities are
                defined, when applicable. For example, having CONFIDENTIAL data implies that some
                users will have authorizations that grant access whereas others don't. Some examples
                are:</p>
            <p>- C_LEVEL = User is a C-level (e.g. CEO, COO, etc.) individual that has a more
                privileged level of access to data (e.g. will be allowed to see CONFIDENTIAL).</p>
            <p>- DOCTOR = User can see all data about a patient, such as PII.</p>
            <p>- ANALYST = User can only see NonPII data for running reports, etc.</p>
            <p> </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The result of 1a &amp; 1b will define the Data Visibilities and User Authorizations
                that will be created.</p>
            <p>2. Identify the allowed combinations of User Authorizations and Data Visibilities for
                accessing data. Note that the examples included some of these combinations for
                illustration purposes. However, the explicit combinations should be driven by
                business compliant access to data.</p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>For example:</p>
            <p>- Access Policy 1 = Users that are DOCTOR can access PII data.</p>
            <p>- Access Policy 2 = Users that are ANALYST or DOCTOR can access NonPII data.</p>
            <p>It's important to note that an Access Policy is associated with a collection of data.
                This means that some data can be governed by one Access Policy, and others by
                different Access Policies. So, for example, this means Access Policies can be
                conflicting, since only one can be associated with a collection of Data.</p>
            <p>For example:</p>
            <p>- Access Policy 3 = Users that are ANALYST can access PII data.</p>
            <p>This is inconsistent with Access Policy 1, but this is permitted because each Access
                Policy is associated with different collections of data, and it's entirely
                reasonable that there might be some data, that even though it contains PII, should
                be accessible by users that are not DOCTORs. </p>
            <?oxy_custom_end?>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd/>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
