<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_doc_intro_semios">
 <title>Introduction</title>
 <conbody>
  <p>This document specifies the high level architecture for Semios system integration with PHEMI
   Central. It describes the Semios - PHEMI Central system integration points and their use, and the
   deployment and configuration of PHEMI Central for Semios.</p>
  <p>M2M integration with PHEMI Central is achieved with the PHEMI REST interface, which is also
   used internally by PHEMI Central's Web and Command Line interfaces. The PHEMI REST interface
   provides the capability to write data into the system (ingest) and read data from the system
   (query). </p>
  <p>The Semios system uses PHEMI Central in a headless configuration utilizing the PHEMI REST
   interface. Semios raw sensor data is ingested into the system using this interface. Queries are
   conducted on Semios raw and derived data (e.g. sensor aggregation) using the same interface. For
   example, the Semios App Server queries PHEMI Central to provide analytical information back to
   users to satisfy the Semios “Read Logs” and “Drill Down” use cases.</p>
  <p>During ingestion the sensor data are stored, processed and aggregated. The parsing, processing
   and aggregation tasks are done by custom Data Processing Functions (DPFs). The resulting data
   structures support the following calculations at scale by providing appropriate sensor
   aggregations:</p>
  <ul id="ul_nv2_v41_fq">
   <li>Degree Days</li>
   <li>Frost</li>
   <li>Fireblight</li>
  </ul>
  <p>PHEMI Central provides efficient and scalable methods utilizing aggregations to calculate
   running averages, summations, minimums and maximums of the Semios data. To describe sets of
   aggregated data, sets are tagged with user defined labels, such as ‘Block’, ‘Property’ or ‘Crop
   Type’. By using the aggregations, the task of calculating combinatory values is aided and
   accelerated by PHEMI Central, simplifying the Semios application. </p>
  <p>The following diagram illustrates the high level architecture of the Semios-PHEMI integration.
   The flow of data between PHEMI Central and the Semios components is managed by the PHEMI REST
   interface.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
