<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-policies">
 <title>Data Policies</title>
 <shortdesc>The data policy provides several key items of information about a data collection. </shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>The data policy describes what type and format of data is expected from the data source and
   classifies the data collection into one of the configured data categories. The data policy also
   lists the users who "own," or are responsible for, various aspects of the information.</p>
  <p>The data policy also specifies the privacy settings for the data collection. It specifies which
   data visibilities, if any, to attach to data belonging to this collection. The data policy also
   specifies which access policy (if any) will be used to enforce rightful access to the
   information. All raw data ingested from this data collection, as well as every item of data
   derived from processing this data collection, will be tagged on ingestion with the specified data
   visibility and access policy to protect privacy.</p>
  <p>The data policy is also where the data sharing agreement is stored for reference. In this
   context, the data sharing agreement is the document recording permission for this data collection
   to be stored in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. You upload the agreement document
   and specify the time period for which the agreement is valid.</p>
  <p>The data policy also records the retention rules to be applied to information from this data
   source. The system uses the retention rules and looks at the ingest timestamp to calculate a time
   to live for each data element. When the time to live expires, <ph
    conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> deletes the raw data and all associated derived data
   items from its data store.</p>
  <p>If you want your information to be version-controlled, the data policy is the place where you
   enable version control.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
