<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA General Task//EN" "generalTask.dtd">
<task id="task_define-dpf">
    <title>Specify the Data Processing Function</title>
    <shortdesc>To associate a Data Processing Function (DPF) with a data collection, you upload the
        DPF archive onto the <uicontrol>Data Processing Function</uicontrol> screen of the
            <wintitle>Data Collections</wintitle> page.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>
                <xref href="../DPFs/con_dpfs.xml#concept_dpfs">Tell me about DPFs and DPF
                    archives.</xref></p>
            <p>To associate a DPF with a data collection:</p>
        </context>
        <steps id="steps_qxv_jfq_yq">
            <step>
                <cmd>On the <wintitle>Data Policy</wintitle> screen of the <wintitle>Data
                        Collections</wintitle> page, click the <uicontrol>Data Processing
                        Function</uicontrol> tab.</cmd>
                <info>The <wintitle>Data Processing Function</wintitle> screen opens. When you first
                    define a data collection, no DPF is associated with it. <fig
                        id="fig_data-source-no-dpf">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/data-collections_no-dpf.png"
                            id="image_cfz_r14_1r" scale="50"/>
                    </fig></info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Add a DPF</uicontrol> button. </cmd>
                <info>The <wintitle>Apply DPF for this Data Collection</wintitle> screen opens. <fig
                        id="fig_apply-dpf">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/data-collections_apply-dpf.png"
                            id="image_gsj_hd4_1r" scale="50"/>
                    </fig></info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Choose to use either a <uicontrol>System DPF</uicontrol> or a <uicontrol>Custom
                        DPF</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <choices id="choices_zrx_2b4_1r">
                    <choice>A system DPF is one of the standard DPF libraries provided with <ph
                            conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. If you choose <wintitle>System
                            DPF</wintitle>, use the drop-down arrow to select which PHEMI system DPF
                        you want to use. Choose between a DPF for processing <uicontrol>Variant Call
                            Format (VCF) data</uicontrol> and a DPF for processing
                            <uicontrol>Microsoft Excel workbook</uicontrol> data. Once the system
                        DPF is selected, click the <uicontrol>Apply System DPF</uicontrol> button to
                        apply the DPF.</choice>
                    <choice>A custom DPF is a DPF you develop especially to process your
                        organization's data. If you choose <wintitle>Custom DPF</wintitle>, click
                        the <uicontrol>Select File</uicontrol> button, navigate to the DPF archive
                        and double-click the ZIP file. Or, drag and drop the DPF archive from your
                        file manager oto the target area on the <ph
                            conkeyref="product-vars/gui-name"/> screen. Click the <uicontrol>Apply
                            Custom DPF</uicontrol> button to upload the archive file and apply the
                        DPF.</choice>
                </choices>
                <info>
                    <p>The system uploads the DPF, validates it, and applies it. The <wintitle>Data
                            Processing Function</wintitle> screen reappears, showing the DPF name,
                        the DPF version, the default trigger condition, and the DPF description. All
                        information except the trigger is automatically read from the DPF archive or
                        derived by <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>'s <ph
                            conkeyref="product-vars/dpf-framework"/>.</p>
                    <fig id="fig_data-collections_dpf">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/data-collections_dpf.png"
                            id="image_pll_4hh_fr" scale="50"/>
                    </fig>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Set the trigger condition.  The trigger condition determines when the DPF
                    processes ingested data.</cmd>
                <choicetable id="choicetable_arl_13h_fr" relcolwidth="1* 3*">
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>
                            <p>When new data arrives</p>
                        </choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>The DPF processes data as it is ingested.</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>
                            <p>Manually</p>
                        </choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>The DPF must be manually triggered.</p>
                            <p>When you choose this option, an <uicontrol>Execute</uicontrol> button
                                appears next to the Trigger field. Click this button to manually
                                execute a DPF on a data collection.</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>
                            <p>Periodic</p>
                        </choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>The DPF executes on ingested data according to the specified
                                schedule. When  you choose this option, a scheduling field
                                appears.</p>
                            <p>Set the DPF schedule to execute every <uicontrol>1
                                minute</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>5 minutes</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>10
                                    minutes</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>30 minutes</uicontrol>, or
                                    <uicontrol>60 minutes</uicontrol>. By default, the DPF executes
                                every 5 m</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                </choicetable>
                <info>By default, the DPF trigger is set to execute the DPF every 5 minutes.</info>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
