<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_view-password-policy">
    <title>View the Password Policy</title>
    <shortdesc>Use the <wintitle>Password Policy</wintitle> screen of the <wintitle>System
            Configuration</wintitle> page to see the configured password policy.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <steps id="steps_dwd_rnx_kq">
            <step>
                <cmd>Open the <uicontrol>System Configuration</uicontrol> page, by clicking the
                        <uicontrol>System Configuration</uicontrol> icon <image
                        href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/icon_system-config.JPG"
                        id="image_svp_vkn_jq"/> in the left navigation bar.</cmd>
                <info>The <wintitle>System Configuration</wintitle> page opens on the<wintitle>
                        Password Policy</wintitle> screen.<fig id="fig_password-policy">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/password-policy.jpg"
                            id="image_j4l_xkn_jq"/>
                    </fig></info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Set the password policy information.</cmd>
                <choicetable id="choicetable_h54_rtx_3q">
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Minimum Length</choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>Mandatory. The minimum length for the password. The range is 6 to 15.
                                The default is 6.</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Maximum Length</choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>Mandatory. The maximum length for the password. The maximum starts at
                                the value set for <wintitle>Minimum Length</wintitle> (that is,
                                maximum and minimum value can be the same) and ranges to 32
                                characters. The default is 32.</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Can't reuse <i>n</i>passwords</choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>Optional. Specifies the number of times in a row a password can be
                                used. For example, if this value is set to 1, the user cannot reuse
                                the same password twice; at least one more password must intervene
                                before reusing the original password. The range is 0 to 12. The
                                default is 0, which means that the same password can be repeated
                                indefinitely. </p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Non-Alpha Character</choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>Optional. Specifies whether the password must include with a
                                non-alphabetical character. Non-alphabetical characters are numbers
                                or special characters. Spaces are not supported. Supported values
                                are as follows: </p>
                            <ul id="ul_tbz_jqx_kq">
                                <li><keyword>Required</keyword>: Passwords must include at least one
                                    non-alphabetical character.</li>
                                <li><keyword>Optional</keyword>: Passwords can consist of only
                                    alphabetic characters.</li>
                            </ul>
                            <p>The default is <keyword>Optional</keyword>.</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>First/Last non-numeric characters</choption>
                        <chdesc><p>Optional. Specifies whether the password must begin and end with
                                a non-numeric character. Non-numeric characters include alphabetical
                                characters and special characters. Spaces are not supported.
                                Supported values are as follows: </p><ul id="ul_hnw_wqx_kq">
                                <li><keyword>Required</keyword>: Passwords must begin and end with a
                                    non-numeric character.</li>
                                <li><keyword>Optional</keyword>: Passwords may begin and end with
                                    alphabetic or special characters.</li>
                            </ul>The default is <keyword>Optional</keyword>.</chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>User ID in Password</choption>
                        <chdesc>
                            <p>Optional. Specifies whether the string representing the user's ID may
                                appear in the password. Supported values are as follows:</p>
                            <ul id="ul_uqk_hsx_kq">
                                <li><keyword>Disallowed</keyword>: The user ID may not appear in the
                                    password.</li>
                                <li><keyword>Allowed</keyword>: The user ID may appear in the
                                    password.</li>
                            </ul>
                            <p>The default is <keyword>Allowed</keyword>.</p>
                        </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                </choicetable>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Save the password policy information by clicking the
                        <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> button. </cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
