<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_PHEMI-Central-ovw">
 <title><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> Overview</title>
 <shortdesc><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> uses powerful big data technologies with
    advanced data management capabilities to reliably store data at scale.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
    <p>
      <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> draws on the Hadoop ecosystem for linear scale and
      reliable distributed data storage across large clusters of low-cost commodity servers. In
      contrast to conventional Hadoop-based systems, though, PHEMI Central is a fully integrated
      enterprise-grade system. </p>
    <p> However, PHEMI Central adds significantly more functionality. Ussers don’t need to worry
      about digging deep into the world of Hadoop, MapReduce, YARN, Pig, HIVE, Sqoop, HBase,
      Zookeeper, Accumulo, and so on. Commodity Hardware PHEMI Central eliminates the cost and
      performance bottlenecks associated with expensive Storage Area Network (SAN) or Network
      Attached Storage (NAS) architectures. The system uses low cost, commodity hardware components
      and direct attached disk drives to significantly lower the cost of ownership compared to
      traditional enterprise data warehouse systems. Scalability and Performance PHEMI Central can
      easily aggregate structured and unstructured data, scaling storage and compute linearly from
      terabytes to petabytes with each additional hard drive and node. Reliability and Availability
      All data stored in PHEMI Central is replicated three times across the system to ensure high
      availability and resiliency in the event of a hardware failure. Direct attached hard drives
      can be hot swapped without impacting performance or data availability while larger or faster
      drives and nodes can are absorbed into the system and load balanced automatically. LDAP
      integration PHEMI Central can operate with your existing LDAP or Active Directory identity
      management systems or via internally managed PHEMI Central user accounts. Maintenance and
      Support PHEMI Central provides clear visibility into overall system health, diagnostics,
      troubleshooting, capacity and digital assets under management so that IT administrators can
      quickly configure and test all nodes. Additionally, with Apache Ambari, system management
      capabilities can be integrated with IT infrastructure monitoring tools such as Microsoft
      System Center, Teradata Viewpoint, Nagios and Ganglia.</p>
    <?oxy_custom_end?>
  </conbody>
</concept>
