<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_config-data-ingestion">
  <title>Data Ingestion</title>
  <shortdesc/>
  <conbody>
    <p>The process of inputting data into the system is referred to as <i>ingestion</i>. The system
      ingests and processes input documents. </p>
    <p>The document ingested by the system is considered the <i>raw data</i>.</p>
    <p>As part of document ingestion, the system will annotate the document with <i>meta data
      </i>which describes the document. Meta data is not generated by examining the contents of the
      ingested document, but rather by looking at the document from an external point of view. For
      example, meta data includes descriptive information such as the data collection the document was
      ingested into, the timestamp when the document was ingested, the name of the document and
      more. The full list of descriptive meta data is provided in the <xref href="#h.mcgwqoeixf7a"
        >DPF Meta Data</xref> section in the Appendix.</p>
    <p>The ingested document can be processed further with a Data Processing Function (DPF). The
      data generated by the DPF is considered <i>derived data</i>. The DPF generated data is done by
      analyzing the ingested document and producing additional information. Any information that
      requires analyzing the contents of the document is considered derived data such as data mined
      information, calculated information and inferred information. For a list of derived data and
      their types for Semios, please see the <xref href="#h.cawmi2xfwosa">DPF Processed Tags</xref>
      and <xref href="#h.entv9b4z26pg">DPF Processed Data</xref> sections in the Appendix.</p>
    <p>The DPF can also generate information that system will aggregate over specific time based
        <i>bins.</i> The data generated by the system based on the information provided by the DPF
      is considered <i>aggregated data</i>. The bin types specified in <xref href="#h.oiix1huwmm2k"
        >Query Aggregate Data</xref>. The aggregated data is specified in <xref
        href="#h.1xkitfqorgd1">Data Aggregations</xref>.</p>
    <p>To summarize, there are four types of data:</p>
    <ul id="ul_xdv_d23_fq">
      <li><u>Raw Data</u>: The input document provided by an external entity</li>
      <li><u>Metadata</u>: Descriptive information about the input document gathered without
        examining the contents of the input document</li>
      <li><u>Derived Data</u>: Data mined, calculated or inferred data generated by a DPF by
        analyzing the contents of the input document</li>
      <li><u>Aggregated Data</u>: Calculated time-based data</li>
    </ul>
  </conbody>
</concept>
