<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_datasets">
 <title>Datasets</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p>A dataset is a specific view of data in the PHEMI system that is accessible to some limited set
   of users. The view can be across multiple data sources.</p>
  <p>Data sets are typically created for a research or exploratory data use falling outside the
   bounds of governance and controls protecting the source data. Each dataset must be associated
   with an access polcy to ensure that it complies with the criteria that were established in the
   authorization to create it.</p>
  <p> You can define any number of datasets. Defining a dataset has no impact on configuration for
   data sources or protections to data. Data Source configurations and protections to data. The only
   requirement is that an Access Policy must be associated with the dataset to ensure that it
   complies with the criteria that were established in the authorization to create it.</p>
  <p><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>A subset of the elements
   produced by Data Processing Functions are selected to define a dataset that will be materialized
   in HANA. The chosen Access Policies determine the data representation (e.g. identified or
   de-identified) that is persisted in HANA.<?oxy_custom_end?></p>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p>A Dataset refers to a specific, cross-data-source view of data in the system that is accessible
   to a limited set of users. These are typically created for research or exploratory uses of data
   that falls outside of the bounds of the protections and controls that protect the source data
   (i.e. the Governance specified for each Data Source).</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>Any number of Datasets can be created, with no impact on the existing Data Source
   configurations and protections to data. The only requirement is that an Access Policy must be
   associated with the dataset to ensure that it complies with the criteria that were established in
   the authorization to create it.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
 </conbody>
</concept>
