<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_datasets">
 <title>Datasets</title>
 <shortdesc>A dataset is a specific view of data in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"
  />.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>Datasets are virtual constructs, created by selecting data elements from across all of the
   digital assets data collections stored in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. You can
   contsruct a dataset using any available data elements, across multiple and disparate data
   collections. They can be created in advance or on demand, and they can be altered whenever
   circumstances dictate. You don't have to predefine the data and you don't have to navigate a
   complex database schema. </p>
  <p> To be able to define a dataset, a user must have a role of <ph conkeyref="product-vars/admin"
   />. To be able to execute or export a dataset, a user must have a role of <ph
    conkeyref="product-vars/data-analyst"/>. </p>
  <p>Datasets are instantiated only when they are executed. Datasets can be be executed directly by
   users and downloaded or exported to spreadsheets, applications, or analytics tools. Because all
   data is indexed and cataloged in advance, dataset execution is fast.</p>
  <p>Defining a dataset does not modify any configuration for data collections or impact any
   protections to data, because the <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> Policy Enforcement
   Engine mediates all requests for data. Users can only access and export data to which they have
   rightful access, based on data visibility tags, user authorizations, and access policies, so
   access to data remains governance-compliant at all times. </p>
  <p>Datasets are often created for research or exploratory data use. As such, the intended use for
   a given dataset may be different from the intended use of the original data collections. In
   particular, the governance and controls intended for the data in a dataset may differ from the
   governance of the original data collections. In <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, you
   can attach an access policy to a dataset that is different from, and independent of, the access
   rules applied to the consistuent data collections.</p>
  <p>Similarly, a single dataset can be executed by multiple users—even by users with different
   authorizations. A given user's actual view into the data in an executed dataset is always
   mediated by the Policy Enforcement Engine, and is therefore restricted by  data visibility and
   user authorization, as experssed in an access policy. Thus, two users with different
   authorizations might execute the same dataset but end up with different views of the data.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
