<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_datasets">
 <title>Datasets</title>
 <shortdesc>A dataset is a specific view of data in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"
  />.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>Datasets are virtual constructs, created by selecting data elements from across all of the
   digital assets stored in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. You can construct a dataset
   using any available data elements, across multiple and disparate data collections. They can be
   created in advance or on demand, and they can be altered whenever circumstances dictate. You
   don't have to predefine the data and you don't have to navigate a complex database schema. </p>
  <p> To be able to define a dataset, a user must have a role of <ph conkeyref="role-vars/admin"/>.
   To be able to execute or export a dataset, a user must have a role of <ph
    conkeyref="role-vars/data-analyst"/>. </p>
  <p>Datasets are instantiated only when they are executed. Datasets can be executed directly by
   users and downloaded or exported to spreadsheets, applications, or analytics tools. </p>
  <p>Defining a dataset does not modify any configuration for data collections or impact any
   protections to data, because the <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>
   <ph conkeyref="product-vars/policy-engine"/> mediates all requests for data. Users can only
   access and export data to which they have rightful access, based on data visibility tags, user
   authorizations, and access policies, so access to data remains governance-compliant at all times. </p>
  <p>Datasets are often created for research or exploratory data use. As such, the intended use for
   a given dataset may be different from the intended use of the original data collections. In
   particular, the governance and controls intended for the data in a dataset may differ from the
   governance of the original data collections. In <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, you
   can attach an access policy to a dataset that is different from, and independent of, the access
   rules applied to the constituent data collections. </p>
  <p>When you attach an access policy to a dataset, the dataset bypasses any access policies
   protecting the constituent data collections and instead is constrained by its own access policy.
   For example, the access policy of a data collection may specify that only a user with
    <keyword>Doctor</keyword> authorization may see data with <keyword>PHI</keyword> visibility,
   while the access policy for a dataset including some of the same information may allow users with
    <keyword>Nurse</keyword> authorization to view <keyword>PHI</keyword> data. </p>
  <p>Similarly, a single dataset can be executed by multiple users—even by users with different
   authorizations. A given user's actual view into the data in an executed dataset is always
   mediated by the <ph conkeyref="product-vars/policy-engine"/>, and is therefore constrained by
   data visibility and user authorization, as expressed in an access policy. Thus, two users with
   different authorizations might execute the same dataset but end up with different views of the
   data.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
