<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_glossary">
 <title>Glossary of Terms and Concepts</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <dl>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>access policy</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">Lowercase (i.e., not "Access Policies").</p>
     <p id="access-policy">An access policy is a set of logical rules that determines how users can
      consume data stored in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>.  The access policy
      specifies what user authorizations are required to interact with data tagged with specified
      sensitivity, or visibility. Access policies can be applied to data sources and datasets. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>authorizations</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">Lowercase (i.e., not "Authorizations").</p>
     <p id="user-authorizations">User authorizations are configurable labels you can assign to <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> users. Authorization definitions are
            configured in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> by the <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/admin"/> in accordance with the organization's governance
            policies. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry audience="internal">
    <dt>big data</dt>
    <dd>Do not capitalize. Do not hyphenate when used as an adjectival phrase (i.e., "big data
     warehouse" not "big-data warehouse").</dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>cell (field)</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="cell">A cell, or field, is the smallest unit of data storage in <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. A cell is a single data item, which can range
            from a single byte up to gigabytes, plus the metadata associated with the data item. Any
            piece of raw data, regardless of size, is stored in a single cell. Elements of derived
            data (transformed from the raw data) are also each stored individually in cells. Any
            cell can be protected by applying data visibilities.For derived data, each derived item
            can be individually assigned a visibility (which may be different than that configured
            for the data source) by the DPF performing the processing.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>code library</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="code-library">A code library is a package of executable code that is included in a DPF
      archive. Whether the code is source or compiled depends on the coding language. Code libraries
      must be portable and self-contained; that is, all dependencies required for the DPF to
      function must be bundled inside the library, in the appropriate way, for whatever language is
      being used.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>dataset</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">One word (i.e., not "data set").</p>
     <p id="dataset">A dataset is a view, or map, of an underlying set of data. Data items in a
            dataset can be selected from across multiple data sources. The dataset is a view, or
            map, to the underlying data. The actual content of the dataset (that is, the dataset's
            data) is generated when the dataset is executed or when it is queried against.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>data category</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">Not "data source category" or "datasource category."</p>
     <p>Data categories are a way to classify data into broader groupings. Examples of data
      categories are "Research Reports," "X-Rays," and "Prescriptions."</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Data Processing Function, DPF</dt>
        <dd>
          <p audience="internal">Capitalized.</p>
          <p id="dpf"> A Data Processing Function, or DPF, is an executable piece of code that
            supplies the instructions for processing raw data (for example, a log message or medical
            report) to extract from heterogeneous data sources meaningful, context-specific
            information (such as a temperature reading or blood glucose measurement) that can be
            queried or exported for analysis. The code is executed by the <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>
            <ph conkeyref="product-vars/dpf-engine"/>, which uses it to direct curation of the data.
            The input to a DPF is the raw binary data ingested into the system. The output of a DPF
            is a set of structured elements, each of which includes a type property (for example,
            INT or STRING) and can specify data visibilities (for example, SECRET or IDENTIFIABLE)
            on a per-field basis. The data elements output by a DPF are called derived data. The
            collection of derived data produced by a DPF is automatically indexed in PHEMI Central.
          </p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>data source</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">Two words (i.e., not "datasource").</p>
     <p id="data-source">In <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, a data source is the set of
            management and governance rules and policies that will be applied to a collection of
            data. A data source configuration should be defined for each collection of data to be
            stored and managed according to the same retention, legal, and governance rules. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>data visibilities</dt>
    <dd>See <keyword>visibilities</keyword>.</dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>derived data</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="derived-data">Derived data is data that has been parsed, extracted, or otherwise
      enriched or processed by running a DPF on stored raw data. The set of derived data items can
      be searched, queried, further processed, or exported from the system. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>digital asset</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="digital-asset">A digital asset is any piece of data stored with metadata in the system.
      This may be raw data that has had metadata applied on collection, or it may be derived data
      that has been parsed, indexed, catalogued, and/or enriched with additional metadata. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>DPF archive</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">Note that "archive" is lower case.</p>
     <p id="dpf-archive">A DPF archive is the set of code that makes up a DPF. A DPF archive is
      delivered as a ZIP file archive. It consists of two parts: a manifest file and a code library.
      To associate a DPF with a data source, the DPF archive is ``registered`` with the data source
      by uploading the archive during data source configuration.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>ingestion</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="ingestion">Ingestion is the process by which data is brought into in <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>. The sending system (the data source) submits
            the data to <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, which listens for the data
            using a web service. Data can also be ingested manually, by using the <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>
            <ph conkeyref="product-vars/gui-name"/>. The specific characteristics of data ingestion
            can be specified per data source as part of the data source configuration. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>JSON</dt>
    <dd>
     <p>JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation. JSON is a lightweight data-interchange format
            that is easy for humans to read and write and easy for machines to parse and generate.
            JSON is used in the body of several REST requests in the PHEMI RESTful API. <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> also includes a system DPF that can create
            derived data from JSON objects, providing the objects conform to PHEMI’s JSON
            specification.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>key-value pairs</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="key-value-pair">A key-value pair is a set of two linked data items: a key which uniquely
      identifies some item of data, and the data itself. PHEMI Central uses key-value store to
      efficiently store, process, and retrieve data.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>M2M</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="m2m">M2M is a way of referring to machine-to-machine interfaces, used in
      machine-to-machine communication.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>manifest file</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="manifest-file">A manifest file is a JSON file that specifies the output of a DPF. With
      the code library, the manifest file makes up the DPF archive that is uploaded to register the
      DPF with a data source. The manifest file should include the properties of the DPF along with
      the details of each derived data item to be generated. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>metadata</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">One word (i.e., not "meta data")</p>
     <p id="metadata">Metadata is information about a piece of data. In <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, metadata is information about how a given
            piece of data is to be managed. When a piece of raw data is ingested into <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, information from the connection (for example,
            the timestamp) together with policy information configured for the data source (for
            example, the data visibility) and some derived information (for example, a "time to
            live," as derived from the timestamp and the data retention policy) is used to create
            metadata properties that are stored with the data. Further, <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> also automatically indexes and catalogues all
            stored data, whether raw or derived; the indexes and catalogues can also be considered a
            kind of metadata.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>PII</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="pii">Personally Identifiable Information, or PII, is a legal concept used in US privacy
      law and information security to mean information that can be used on its own or with other
      information to identify, contact, or locate a single person or to identify an individual in
      context. When thinking about PII, it is important to distinguish legal requirements to remove
      attributes uniquely identify an individual from a general technical ability to identify
      individuals. Because of the versatility and power of modern re-identification algorithms,
      together with the amount of information freely available from all sources, the absence of PII
      data does not guarantee that de-identified data cannot be used, perhaps in combination with
      other data, to identify individuals.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>privacy-level visibilities</dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Privacy-level visibilities are data visibilities that characterize the privacy level of a
            data item. <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> includes predefined privacy-level
            visibilities designed to apply to data domains where privacy is important.</p>
     <ul id="ul_wt5_bsm_jq">
      <li><b>IDENTIFIED</b>. The data contains Personally Identifying Information that potentially
       identifies an individual. Examples of information of this type include name, Social Insurance
       Number, and date of birth. </li>
      <li><b>DE-IDENTIFIED</b>. The data contains IDENTIFIED information that has been masked or
       encrypted.</li>
      <li><b>NON-IDENTIFIED</b>. The data is not identifying in and of itself. Examples of this type
       of information include weight or favorite food. </li>
     </ul>
     <p>Although privacy-level visibilities are preconfigured, their descriptions can be modified by
      configuration.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry audience="internal">
    <dt>privacy, security, and governance</dt>
    <dd>Always use the same order. Do not capitalize (unless in a heading or title).</dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry audience="internal">
    <dt>Privacy by Design</dt>
    <dd>Title case (i.e., capitalize "Privacy" and "Design"; not "by"). If shortened, the acronym is
     "PbD."</dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>raw data</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="raw-data">In <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/>, raw data items are files,
            objects, records, images, and so on that are submitted for ingestion into the system.
            Raw data is stored exactly as received, along with the metadata generated for it on
            ingestion. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>REST, RESTful API</dt>
    <dd>
     <p audience="internal">"REST" is all caps. The "ful" in "RESTful" is lower case.</p>
     <p id="rest">Representational Statement Transfer (REST) is an architectural style that uses
      HTTP requests and associated methods (POST, PUT, GET, and DELETE) to create, update, read, and
      delete data. A RESTful API is an application programming interface (API) based on REST. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <dl>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>visibilities</dt>
    <dd>
     <p id="visibilities">All raw data and derived data stored in <ph
              conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> can be tagged with labels that provide
            information about the data's sensitivity. This sensitivity is described in terms of the
            visibility the data should have to different system users. The visibility tags you
            define for your data should reflect the sensitivity of the data as identified by your
            organization. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry audience="internal">
    <dt>ZIP file</dt>
    <dd>
     <p>"ZIP" is all caps.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
 </conbody>
</concept>
