<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_access-policies">
 <title>Access Policies</title>
 <shortdesc>Access policies let you characterize rightful access in terms of user authorizations and
    data visibility.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
    <p conref="../_glossary/con_glossary.xml#concept_glossary/access-policy"/>
    <p>To create an access policy, you define one or more access rules. Each rule has three parts. </p>
    <ul id="ul_l4z_2dm_lq">
      <li>
        <p><keyword>Subject</keyword> specifies who may access the data. Access is characterized in
          terms of user authorizations. </p>
        <p><xref href="../users/con_user-authorizations.xml#concept_user-authorizations">Tell me
            about user authorizations.</xref></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><keyword>Action</keyword> specifies what action authorized users may take to interact
          with the data.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><keyword>Object</keyword> specifies what kind of data for which the access is being
          granted. The data is specified in terms of data visibility. </p>
        <p><xref href="../data_visibilities/con_data-visibilities.xml#concept_data-visibilities"
            >Tell me about data visibilities.</xref></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p> A access policy is matched when the request satisfies at least one access rule in the
      policy. A rule is satisfied if the user making the request has one of the authorizations
      listed for <keyword>Subject</keyword>, and the data being requested one of the visibilities
      listed for <keyword>Object</keyword>. When there is a match, the user may take the specified
      action(s) on the data.</p>
    <p>The rules in a given access policy are intended to implement specific controls over data.
      Depending on the number and kinds of datasets your organization works with, you may need just
      one access policy or you may need multiple access policies. </p>
    <p>If you have multiple access policies, it is possible for policies to conflict with one
      another and still represent a consistent governance policy, provided that each access policy
      is used to control different data collections or datasets. For example, one access policy may
      allow users with <keyword>Researcher</keyword> authority to read
        <keyword>CONFIDENTIAL</keyword> data while another access policy does not. This can be
      perfectly consistent, given the policies control different data.</p>
  </conbody>
</concept>
