<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_access-policies">
 <title>Access Policies</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
    <p><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Data Owners can create
      Access Policies by constructing logical rules that combine user authorizations with object
      attributes for feeding data from PHEMI Central into HANA. Rules are combined by a logical “or”
      operation that enables a wide range of access policies to be created (eg. A doctor can view
      identified patient information when logged on from the hospital
      network).<?oxy_custom_end?></p>
    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
    <p>An Access Policy is a combination of Data Visibilities, User Authorizations, and Actions that
      specify an allowed Access to data in PHEMI Central. Any number of Access Policies can be
      created, and they don't conflict or limit existing ones when new ones are created. </p>
    <p> </p>
    <p>The purpose of an Access Policy is to define a "lens" or "view" into data that determines
      what user authorizations are required to action with data that has specified labels.</p>
    <p> </p>
    <p>For example, an Access Policy may state that a user authorization of "SECRET Clearance" is
      required to "Read" data that has the label "PII". This Access Policy can then be associated
      with any number of Data Sources to impose the rule that only SECRET Clearance users can read
      data that is labelled as PII. </p>
    <?oxy_custom_end?>
    <p> </p>
    <p conref="../_Glossary/con_glossary.xml#concept_glossary/access-policy"/>
    <p>To create an access policy, you define one or more access rules. Each rule has three parts. </p>
    <ul id="ul_l4z_2dm_lq">
      <li><keyword>Subject</keyword> specifies who may access the data, by listing the permitted
        user authorizations.</li>
      <li><keyword>Action</keyword> specifies how authorized users may consume the data. </li>
      <li><keyword>Object</keyword> specifies what data the permitted users are allowed to interact
        with, by listing the data visibilities.</li>
    </ul>
    <ul id="ul_qfm_rr4_mq">
      <li>The <keyword>Subject</keyword> specifies a set of the user authorizations. </li>
      <li>The <keyword>Object</keyword> specifies a set of data visibilities. </li>
      <li>The <keyword>Action</keyword> specifies the action to be taken if the rule is
        matched.</li>
    </ul>
    <p> A rule is matched when the user making the request has an authorization matching at least
      one of those listed for <keyword>Subject</keyword>, and the data being requested has a
      visibility matching at least one of those listed for <keyword>Object</keyword>. When there is
      a match, the user may take the specified action(s) on the data.</p>
    <p>If there is more than one access rule within a policy, the rules are related by OR logic.</p>
    <p>The rules in a given access policy are intended to implement specific controls over a
      dataset. Depending on the number and kinds of datasets your organization works with, you may
      need just one access policy or multiple access policies. </p>
    <p>If you have multiple access policies, it is possible for policies to conflict with one
      another and still represent a consistent governance policy, provided that each access policy
      is used to control different data sources or datasets. For example, one access policy may
      allow users with <keyword>Researcher</keyword> authority to read
        <keyword>CONFIDENTIAL</keyword> data while another access policy does not. This can be
      perfectly consistent, given the policies control different data.</p>
  </conbody>
</concept>
