<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_view-data-source-metrics">
    <title>View Data Metrics</title>
    <shortdesc> View statistics about data collections on the <wintitle>Data Collection
            Metrics</wintitle> tab of the <wintitle>System Metrics</wintitle> page.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>To view data collection metrics:</p>
        </context>
        <steps id="steps_jrp_dwf_cr">
            <step>
                <cmd>Open the <uicontrol>System Metrics</uicontrol> page, by clicking the
                        <uicontrol>System Metrics</uicontrol> icon in the left navigation bar.
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/icon_system-metrics.png"
                        id="image_fmr_wzn_mq" scale="50"/></cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>The <wintitle>System Metrics</wintitle> page opens showing the
                            <wintitle>Global Metrics</wintitle> pane and the <wintitle>Data
                            Metrics</wintitle> pane. </p>
                    <fig id="fig_system-metrics">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/system-metrics.png"
                            id="image_hmp_55r_3q" scale="50"/>
                    </fig>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select the data collections to include in the query. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>By default, the <wintitle>Data Metrics</wintitle> pane shows a current
                        snapshot of data collection metrics and includes the data from all data
                        collections. To view information for a different set of data collections,
                        click the drop-down arrow in the <wintitle>Data Collections</wintitle> field
                        and check each data collection you want included in the metrics. If you want
                        to include all data collections, check <wintitle>All</wintitle> to select
                        them all in one operation.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Choose the query period. Select <uicontrol>Now</uicontrol> or select
                        <uicontrol>Date Range</uicontrol> and specify the dates in the format
                        <varname>yyyy</varname><keyword>-</keyword><varname>mm</varname><keyword>-</keyword><varname>dd</varname>.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Query</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>The results of your query are displayed below the selection parameters.</p>
                    <p>If the query period is <wintitle>Now</wintitle>, the system shows the metrics
                        as a set of ring graphs.</p>
                    <fig id="fig_data-metrics_now">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/system-metrics_data_now.png"
                            id="image_xhk_pks_gr" scale="50"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p>When a date range is specified, the system draws an X-Y graph showing
                        ingestion events for the specified data collections. You can hover your
                        cursor over an ingestion event to view specific data metrics for each data
                        collection.</p>
                    <fig id="fig_data-metrics_range">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/system-metrics_data_range.png"
                            id="image_trj_pls_gr" scale="50"/>
                    </fig>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
