<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-consumption">
 <title>Consume</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p>The data elements stored in <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> can be queried in a
   number of ways. You can contructs datasets using any available data element,  across multiple and
   disparate data collections. </p>
  <p>Datasets are virtual constructs that can be created in advance or on demand and altered
   whenever circumstances demand. Datasets are instantiated only when executed. It is not necessary
   to predefine the data needed or to navigate a complex database schema. Datasets can bring
   together any subset of the digital assets in the system, across any data collection of any format
   or type. Because all data is indexed and cataloged in advance, dataset execution is fast.</p>
  <p>The <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> Policy Enforcement Engine mediates all requests
   for data. Users or exporters can only access data based on data privacy tags, user
   authorizations, and access policies, so access to data remains governance-compliant at all times.  </p>
  <fig id="fig_consume">
   <image href="../_images/marketing-diagrams/Consume/consume_focus_architecture.png"
    id="image_dnw_vf4_cr" scale="60"/>
  </fig>
  <p>Datasets can be be executed directly by users and downloaded or exported to spreadsheets,
   applications, or analytics tools. Export can occur in a variety of ways: </p>
  <ul id="ul_m5w_2f4_cr">
   <li>
    <p>To a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet or to a Comma Separated Value (CSV) file </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p>To a custom application via the PHEMI <ph conkeyref="product-vars/RESTful-API"/></p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p>To applications and analytics tools via ODBC/JDBC connectors </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p>To SAP HANA via the SAP Smart Data Access connector </p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p>In all cases, <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> strictly enforces your organization’s
   privacy and security policies to enforce rightful access to data.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
