<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-consumption">
 <title>Consumption</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p/>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p>PHEMI Central has a rich REST API for expressing queries to search for and retrieve data stored
   in the system. Our API supports standard operators, such as:</p>
  <p>Multiple criteria can be combined to create a more restrictive query. Furthermore, PHEMI
   Central supports common data types for these operands, such as INT, DOUBLE, DATE, and TIMESTAMPS.
   The fields queried against (e.g. in the above table <b>ssn </b>or <b>age</b>) are the derived
   data values that are extracted by DPFs, all of which are automatically indexed, making querying
   of the system very efficient. Additionally, all values are tagged with the data attributes,
   preventing users from finding data they are not permitted to see.</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>For users or analytics tools that use SQL to query a system, PHEMI Central provides an SQL-like
   interface for querying against configured datasets. First, an Administrator defines a dataset by
   selecting the derived data fields that are present in it, such as <b>ssn</b> and <b>age</b>. They
   then assign an Access Policy which determines whether data is filtered (such as the <b>ssn</b>
   field) when a user issues a SQL command against the system.</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>Currently, PHEMI supports HiveQL which is a SQL dialect that closely resembles standard SQL. In
   the future, PHEMI will support complete ANSI-92 SQL in the system.</p>
  <p>PHEMI Central allows you to build datasets on demand without having to manage multiple data
   marts or complex MapReduce or YARN processes. Whether the dataset is consumed by a user or
   exported to an application or analytics tool, PHEMI Central strictly enforces your organization’s
   privacy and security policies to ensure appropriate access to data.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
  <p><?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>Dataset destinations and
   data source connections are configured initially based on the parameters of the connection type
   (ODBC, FTP, and JSON-REST).<?oxy_custom_end?></p>
  <p>PHEMI Central integrates with your existing infrastructure, applications, and analytics tools
   to let you immediately take advantage of the Big Data Warehouse. Multiple users can concurrently
   interact with the system, accessing datasets via SQL, data exports, and using custom
   applications, breaking down the costly data silos spread throughout your organization.</p>
  <p>Dataset Access Datasets can be accessed in a variety of ways: • Export to a Microsoft Excel
   spreadsheet or Comma Separated Value (CSV) file • Custom application via the PHEMI REST API •
   Applications and analytics tools via ODBC/ JDBC connectors • SAP HANA via the SAP Smart Data
   Access connector</p>
  <p>On Demand Datasets Datasets are instantiated when information is needed, without having to
   predefine or navigate complex relational database schema. Data views are logical mappings that
   define a subset of the cataloged digital assets in the system across a specified collection of
   data. They can be created, altered, and discarded, and, since they are virtual constructs, they
   eliminate any need for data marts.</p>
  <p>Data Analysis PHEMI Central supports standard tools, including R, SAP, SAS, SPSS, Stata,
   Tableau and more, to let organizations leverage their existing software.</p>
  <p>SQL Support SQL remains the primary method for analyzing and accessing data in many logical
   data warehouse architectures. PHEMI Central supports batch and interactive SQL queries.</p>
  <p>In-house developers, PHEMI developers, or third-party developers can develop custom
   applications using the PHEMI REST web services interface. The REST interface provides a rich set
   of statements that can access core system functionality, including flexible queries for data.
   REST queries, like all other queries are subject to the access controls enforcing information
   privacy, security and governance. Organizations can quickly trial innovative new applications,
   putting information in the hands of their users. This development agility means that applications
   that gain traction can be hardened and expanded and others retired.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
