<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-collection">
 <title>Collection</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p>PHEMI Central has a rich REST API for expressing queries to search for and retrieve data stored
   in the system. Our API supports standard operators, such as:</p>
  <p>Multiple criteria can be combined to create a more restrictive query. Furthermore, PHEMI
   Central supports common data types for these operands, such as INT, DOUBLE, DATE, and TIMESTAMPS.
   The fields queried against (e.g. in the above table <b>ssn </b>or <b>age</b>) are the derived
   data values that are extracted by DPFs, all of which are automatically indexed, making querying
   of the system very efficient. Additionally, all values are tagged with the data attributes,
   preventing users from finding data they are not permitted to see.</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>For users or analytics tools that use SQL to query a system, PHEMI Central provides an SQL-like
   interface for querying against configured datasets. First, an Administrator defines a dataset by
   selecting the derived data fields that are present in it, such as <b>ssn</b> and <b>age</b>. They
   then assign an Access Policy which determines whether data is filtered (such as the <b>ssn</b>
   field) when a user issues a SQL command against the system.</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>Currently, PHEMI supports HiveQL which is a SQL dialect that closely resembles standard SQL. In
   the future, PHEMI will support complete ANSI-92 SQL in the system.</p>
  <p>PHEMI Central can collect virtually any kind of data—structured (such as database records),
   semi-structured (such as Microsoft Excel or genomic files) or unstructured (such as images,
   machine-collected data, or documents). Data can be ingested and aggregated from multiple
   disparate sources. During collection, PHEMI Central tags each raw data item with user-defined
   metadata, then stores the tagged raw data in PHEMI’s fast, powerful data store. The data store is
   key-value–based and schemaless, so data can be ingested without complex or brittle schemamapping
   exercises.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p>Data Sources PHEMI Central can ingest virtually any kind of data, so organizations can
   consolidate their data silos. Data sources can include any data type from small kilobyte messages
   to large terabyte files: • Database Records — Data extracted from information systems, databases,
   etc. • Structured Non-Relational Data — Spreadsheets, GIS datasets, genomics, machine data, XML,
   JSON, HL7, PHEMI Clinical, PHEMI Forms Server, etc. • Semi-structured — ECGs, tabular documents,
   etc. • Unstructured files &amp; datasets — Images, consult letters, reports, emails, customer
   feedback, social media, etc.</p>
  <p>Data Import PHEMI Central can import data in a variety of ways: </p>
  <p>• Streaming – Machine-to-machine data sources, such as telemetry and hospital bedside monitors,
   can stream data to PHEMI Central by means of the PHEMI REST interface. </p>
  <p>• Push — Data sources can publish to PHEMI Central using either JDBC or the PHEMI REST
   interface. </p>
  <p>• Pull — Custom connectors based on PHEMI’s REST can be developed to allow PHEMI Central to
   fetch source data from sources. </p>
  <p>• Manual — Files can be manually uploaded to PHEMI Central from a standard browser window. </p>
  <p>• Store by Reference and Action PHEMI Central can reference remote data or a remote dataset
   through a URL, stored procedure, SQL query or REST API. Store by Reference and Store by Action
   operations are ideal for collaboration projects between organizations or when accessing
   third-party datasets where data sharing agreements restrict data from being replicated.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
 </conbody>
</concept>
