<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-curation">
 <title>Curation</title>
 <shortdesc/>
 <conbody>
  <p/>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p><b>process data once it's stored in PHEMI Central?</b></p>
  <p>PHEMI Central is designed to store any data, regardless of schema, reducing the time and cost
   of aggregating and storing heterogeneous data sources. To query and analyse this data, we require
   a method for extracting context specific information from the raw data being stored, so we can
   query for it or create datasets (i.e. relational views) for analysis using conventional
   tools.</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>PHEMI Central provides a powerful framework for users to write Data Processing Functions (DPFs)
   which are short computer programs that map raw data objects to meaningful derived data that can
   be queried or exported for analysis. The input to a DPF is a raw blob of bytes and the output is
   a list of tuples which contain the fields name (e.g. SSN) and the value (e.g. 12345678) [there's
   more powerful capabilities around privacy protection that we'll explain in the next section
   around cell-level security]. The collection of derived data produced is automatically indexed in
   PHEMI Central using our indexing scheme which facilitates constant time lookups for any values in
   the system (e.g. find all data that has SSN==12345678). </p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>DPFs in Java and Python are currently supported; however, the system can be extended to support
   any modern programming language that runs on a Linux OS. PHEMI Central comes with a library of
   helper functions to simplify the development of DPFs. A 2 day training course in DPF development
   is also available.</p>
  <p> </p>
  <p>PHEMI Central system DPFs which can process raw data that is structured according to the PHEMI
   object specification (see documentation) are also available. This eliminates the need for DPF
   coding provided the raw data being consumed from data sources abides by this structure. </p>
  <p>using our indexing scheme which facilitates constant time lookups for any values in the system
   (e.g. find all data that has SSN==12345678). </p>
  <p>PHEMI Central’s powerful data store automatically indexes and catalogs all ingested data, so
   that even the raw data becomes a digital asset. Then PHEMI Central executes user-specifiable data
   processing functions to cleanse, parse, and structure the data—transforming the raw data into
   analytics-ready digital assets. Transformations include sophisticated cataloging and indexing,
   graphs, and tags for quickly finding specific digital assets within petabytes of data.
   Transformation also applies privacy and sensitivity tagging per individual cell of data. With
   PHEMI Central’s audit, version control, and rollback features, the result is full governance of
   findable, manageable digital assets ready for queries by users and consumption by applications
   and analytics tools.</p>
  <p>Indexing and Cataloging Indexing and cataloging functions occur automatically in PHEMI
   Central’s Indexing and Cataloging Engine, making it easier and faster to find and consume data.
   User-defined DPFs enable deeper and more sophisticated indexing and cataloguing, and second-order
   indexes and graph relationships allow data analysts to quickly find and build datasets across
   petabytes of heterogeneous digital assets. Linking datasets with common keys makes it faster and
   easier to build meaningful datasets across many sources. These powerful indexing features mean
   that data can be accessed in milliseconds, without having to wait for MapReduce or YARN jobs to
   complete.</p>
  <p>Schemaless Storage PHEMI Central’s data store is schemaless: both raw and curated data items
   are stored in a binary format that is unaffected by the source and destination schema. This
   approach means that organizations can quickly aggregate new data sources without costly
   redefinition of old schemas. Schemaless storage also permits the organization to extend uses or
   imagine new uses for data as knowledge advances and needs evolve, without concern for migrating
   rigid predefined schemas. Instead, PHEMI Central uses a flexible, powerful, distributed key-value
   store and sophisticated metadata tagging to manage, describe, and govern the data it stores.
   Curated digital assets derived from the raw data are linked to the original raw data, but PHEMI
   Central’s SQL and REST interfaces abstract away from internal linkages and structures, so users
   and applications can focus on data use rather than data janitorial work.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
 </conbody>
</concept>
