<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-collection">
 <title>Collection</title>
 <shortdesc><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> can collect, or "ingest," any type of
  data.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p>Data collections can include any data type from small kilobyte messages to large terabyte
   files. </p>
  <ul id="ul_mh4_q3n_cr">
   <li>
    <p><b>Database records</b>—Data extracted from information systems, databases, and so on. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Structured non-relational data</b>—Spreadsheets, GIS datasets, genomics, machine data,
     XML, JSON, HL7, and so on.</p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Semi-structured files</b>—ECGs, tabular documents, and so on.</p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Unstructured files and datasets</b>—Images, consult letters, reports, e-mails, customer
     feedback, social media, and so on. </p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <fig id="fig_collect">
   <image href="../../_common_source/_images/mktg/collect.png" id="image_kw4_dhc_dr"/>
  </fig>
  <p>Data can be ingested and aggregated from multiple disparate sources, bringing together and
   consolidating data silos. Data can be ingested into in a variety of ways:</p>
  <ul id="ul_o1m_wjn_cr">
   <li><b>Stream</b>—Machine-to-machine data collections, such as telemetry and hospital bedside
    monitors, can stream data to <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> by means of the PHEMI
     <ph conkeyref="product-vars/RESTful-API"/>.</li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Push</b>—Data collections and extract, transform, and load (ETL) tools can publish to <ph
      conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> using either JDBC or the PHEMI <ph
      conkeyref="product-vars/RESTful-API"/>. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Pull</b>—Custom connectors based on the PHEMI <ph conkeyref="product-vars/RESTful-API"/>
     can be deployed to allow <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> to fetch data from
     sources. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Manually Ingest</b>—Files can be manually uploaded to <ph
      conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> from a standard browser window. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p><b>Store by Reference and Action</b>—<ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> can
     reference remote data or a remote dataset through a URL, stored procedure, SQL query, external
     table, or the <ph conkeyref="product-vars/RESTful-API"/>. Applications can also be stored and
     executed, causing external tables or external data to be accessed and pre-processed. </p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p>During ingest, <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> tags each raw data object with
   metadata that describes the data. Metadata governing digital rights management, retention rules,
   data sharing agreements, and privacy policies is applied and enforced. Describing information
   with metadata means that users and applications can query and analyze data based on the data’s
   properties, instead of having to navigate complex directories or schemas to find information. <ph
    conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> then places the tagged digital asset into the data store
   for curation.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
