<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_wnl_hbs_5q">
 <title>Data Management</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
  <p>PHEMI Central’s data management features allow you to manage your organization’s data according
   to the privacy and access policies that govern digital assets being managed within PHEMI
   Central.</p>
  <p>Proper management of data is critical as volumes grow and variety increases. The PHEMI Central
   Data Management and Governance Console provides the primary interface for data management,
   including data management features for privacy, security, and governance.</p>
  <p/>
  <p>Powerful Metadata Framework The power and sophistication of PHEMI Central’s data management
   capability arises from its powerful metadata framework, which extends from end to end across the
   system. Metadata is applied on ingestion and enriched by cataloging, indexing, and invoking data
   processing functions. The result is data description at the element level embedding the rules and
   policies governing the element, as well as configured properties such as the data source
   ownership, retention time (time to live), and what visibility the element should have. For
   example, de-identification, encryption, and masking, along with other privacy restrictions can be
   enforced per data item, at the cell level. </p>
  <p>In a traditional system, a user would have to plan a file-system hierarchy or a database
   schema. Data would be forced to comply with this rigid hierarchy, and everyone just has to hope
   that the design scales and that requirements do not change. When PHEMI Central’s metadata
   framework is deployed with its scalable distributed key-value store (based on Accumulo), users no
   longer need worry about how to structure the system. PHEMI Central structures data automatically,
   on the fly. Data scales to large volumes at minimal cost while still providing fast access, and
   changes to requirements do not necessitate changes to design of the data store.</p>
  <p>Users and integrated applications benefit from the metadata because they can use simple
   web-service calls based on the properties of the data, rather than having to navigate complex
   directories or schemas to find the data they seek.</p>
  <p>Governance Rule Enforcement Most organizations have governance rules and data sharing
   agreements that stipulate how data may be used and shared. Governance rules are instantiated in
   PHEMI Central through configuration, using the PHEMI Central Data Management and Governance
   Console. PHEMI Central manages and enforces data sharing agreements by flagging the sensitivity
   of individual digital assets, tracking the retention period, recording rules around version
   control, and specifying de-identification, encryption, and data access permissions. Automating
   this function at scale across a variety of data sources and types is critical to managing
   privacy, security, and governance. Flexible, Attribute-Based Access Policies: Decoupling Data
   Protection from Data Use PHEMI Central can automatically de-identify, encrypt, or mask personal
   information and enforce privacy based on sophisticated user access privileges and fine-grained
   sharing and consent rules. PHEMI Central stores the fully identified data but strictly controls
   the rightful use of all digital assets. When the user’s access privileges and the recorded data
   sharing agreements dictate, PHEMI Central can invoke a data processing function to de-identify or
   anonymize any information information. Anonymization and deidentification may include disallowing
   access to personally identifiable information, masking certain information, redacting content, or
   may involve more sophisticated data dependency algorithms to reduce the risk of reidentification.
   Centralizing anonymization and de-identification helps reduce data sprawl and reduces the risk of
   data consistency errors.</p>
  <?oxy_custom_end?>
 </conbody>
</concept>
