<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-visibilities">
 <title>Data Visibilities</title>
 <shortdesc>Data visibilities identify the privacy requirements for data.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p conref="../_Glossary/con_glossary.xml#concept_glossary/visibilities"/>
  <p>Data visibility should be defined in your organization's governance policy and is configured in
    <ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> by the <ph conkeyref="product-vars/admin"/>.</p>
  <p><ph conkeyref="product-vars/product-name"/> comes with three data visibilities predefined:</p>
  <table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_zq5_hfw_kq">
   <title>Predefined Data Visibilities</title>
   <tgroup cols="2">
    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
    <thead>
     <row>
      <entry>Visibility</entry>
      <entry>Meaning</entry>
     </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
     <row>
      <entry>IDENTIFIED</entry>
      <entry>Sensitive data that contains identifying information. Such data should be secured and
       available only to authorized personnel.</entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry>DE_IDENTIFIED</entry>
      <entry>Sensitive data that has been transformed and masked to remove identifying
       information</entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry>NONIDENTIFIED</entry>
      <entry>Data that does not contain sensitive or identifying data.</entry>
     </row>
    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </table>
  <p>You can define additional data visibilities to suit your organization's needs. Possible
   examples are CONFIDENTIAL to identify data that is sensitive and requires a user to a certain
   level of access or certification to access, PII to identify Personally Identifiable Information,
   PHI to identify personal health information, or SECRET to identify especially sensitive
   material.</p>
  <note>Once defined, a data visibility may be neither edited nor deleted.</note>
  <p>The data visibilities specified for a data source are referred to in access policies and
   matched against user authorizations to determine what actions, if any, a given user is allowed to
   perform on the data. The access policy can then be applied to a data source or dataset during
   system configuration.</p>
  <p>In addition,  any data visibility defined in the system can be used by a Data Processing
   Function (DPF) to tag any derived data fields. These derived data elements can be assigned
   different privacy levels from the data source and from one another. For example, the Social
   Security Number extracted from a health record can be tagged CONFIDENTIAL if that data visibility
   has been defined in the system. This mechanism provides "cell-level" privacy protection.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
