<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-visibilities">
 <title>Data Visibilities</title>
 <shortdesc>Data visibilities identify the privacy requirements for data.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p conref="../_Glossary/con_glossary.xml#concept_glossary/visibilities"/>
  <p>The visibility of data in your organization should be set out in your organization's governance
   policy. Working from the governance policy,  the <ph conkeyref="product-vars/admin"/> and is
   configured  as part of system configuration.</p>
  <p>You can define data visibilities to suit your organization's needs. Possible examples are
   CONFIDENTIAL to identify data that is sensitive and requires a user to a certain level of access
   or certification to access, PII to identify Personally Identifiable Information, PHI to identify
   personal health information, or SECRET to identify especially sensitive material.</p>
  <note>Once defined, a data visibility may be neither edited nor deleted. The description for the
   visibility can be modified subsequently.</note>
  <p>The data visibilities specified for a data source are referred to in access policies and
   matched against user authorizations to determine what actions, if any, a given user is allowed to
   perform on the data. The access policy can then be applied to a data source or dataset during
   system configuration. <xref
    href="../users/con_user-authorizations.xml#concept_user-authorizations">Tell me about user
    authorizations.</xref>
   <xref href="../access_policies/con_access-policies.xml#concept_access-policies">Tell me about
    access policies.</xref></p>
  <p>In addition, any data visibility defined in the system can be used by a Data Processing
   Function (DPF) to tag any derived data fields. These derived data elements can be assigned
   different privacy levels from the data source and from one another. For example, the Social
   Security Number extracted from a health record can be tagged CONFIDENTIAL if that data visibility
   has been defined in the system. This mechanism provides field-level privacy protection.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
