<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_data-visibilities">
 <title>Data Visibilities</title>
 <shortdesc>Data visibilities identify the privacy requirements for data.</shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <p conref="../_glossary/con_glossary.xml#concept_glossary/visibilities"/>
  <p>The visibility of data in your organization should be set out in your organization's governance
   policy. </p>
  <p><xref href="../Privacy_Security_Governance/con_governance.xml#concept_governance">Tell me about
    governance policies.</xref>
   <xref
    href="../Privacy_Security_Governance/task_define-governance-policy.xml#task_define-governance-policy"
    >How do I define a governance policy?</xref></p>
  <p>Working from the governance policy, the <ph conkeyref="role-vars/admin"/> configures data
      visibilities as part of system configuration.</p>
  <p>You can define data visibilities to suit your organization's needs. Possible examples are
   CONFIDENTIAL to identify data that is sensitive and requires a user to a certain level of access
   or certification to access, PII to identify Personally Identifiable Information, PHI to identify
   personal health information, or SECRET to identify especially sensitive material.</p>
  <note>Once defined, the name of a data visibility may not be edited. To change the name of a user
   visibility, you must delete the visibility and recreate it with the new name.</note>
  <p>The data visibilities specified for a data collection are referred to in access policies and
   matched against user authorizations to determine what actions, if any, a given user is allowed to
   perform on the data. The access policy can then be applied to a data collection or dataset during
   system configuration. </p>
  <p><xref href="../users/con_user-authorizations.xml#concept_user-authorizations">Tell me about
    user authorizations.</xref>
   <xref href="../access_policies/con_access-policies.xml#concept_access-policies">Tell me about
    access policies.</xref></p>
  <p>In addition, any data visibility defined in the system can be used by a Data Processing
   Function (DPF) to selectively tag any derived data fields. The derived data elements can be
   assigned different privacy levels from those of the data collection and from those of one
   another. For example, the Social Security Number extracted from a health record can be tagged
   CONFIDENTIAL if that data visibility has been defined in the system. This mechanism provides
   field-level privacy protection.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
