<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_user-authorizations">
 <title>User Authorizations</title>
 <conbody>
    <p conref="../_glossary/con_glossary.xml#concept_glossary/user-authorizations"/>
    <p>User authorizations are used together with data visibilities to create access policies. The
      access policy matches the authorization against the data visibility to determine what action,
      if any, a user may take with respect to accessing the data. </p>
    <p><xref href="../data_visibilities/con_data-visibilities.xml#concept_data-visibilities">Tell me
        about data visibilities.</xref>
      <xref href="../access_policies/con_access-policies.xml#concept_access-policies">Tell me about
        access policies.</xref></p>
    <p>Some examples of possible user authorizations are as follows: </p>
    <ul id="ul_lsz_53w_kq">
      <li><keyword>C_LEVEL</keyword>: The user is a C-Level individual (for example, CEO, COO, CIO,
        or CTO) with a privileged level of access. Individuals with <keyword>C_LEVEL</keyword>
        authorization, for example, might be permitted to read data with
          <keyword>CONFIDENTIAL</keyword> visibility.</li>
      <li><keyword>DOCTOR</keyword>: A user with <keyword>DOCTOR</keyword> authorization might, for
        example, be permitted to read any information, including personally identifiable information
        or personal health information.</li>
      <li><keyword>ANALYST</keyword>: A user with <keyword>ANALYST</keyword> authorization might be
        restricted to accessing only the de-identified or nonidentified data.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>A user can be assigned multiple authorizations. User authorizations are set by the <ph
        conkeyref="role-vars/admin"/> during system configuration. </p>
    <p>All users are assigned the predefined PUBLIC authorization by default. The PUBLIC
      authorization can subsequently be removed by the <ph conkeyref="role-vars/admin"/>.</p>
    <note>Once defined, a user authorization name cannot be changed. To change the authorization
      name, you must delete the authorization and recreate it with the new name.</note>
  </conbody>
</concept>
