<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_create-new-user">
    <title>Create a New User</title>
    <shortdesc>Create a new user on the <wintitle>Manage Users</wintitle> page. </shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <prereq>Before you can create users, you must configure user authorizations. <xref
                href="task_define-user-authorizations.xml">How do I configure user
                authorizations?</xref></prereq>
        <context>
            <p>To create a new user:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Open the <uicontrol>Manage Users</uicontrol> page, by clicking the
                        <uicontrol>Users</uicontrol> icon in the left navigation bar. <image
                        href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/icon_users.JPG" id="image_svp_vkn_jq"
                        scale="50"/>
                </cmd>
                <info>The <wintitle>Manage Users</wintitle> page lists all users defined in the
                    system so far.<fig id="fig_manage-users">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/users_manage-users.jpg"
                            id="image_j4l_xkn_jq" scale="70"/>
                    </fig></info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Create User</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
                <info>The <wintitle>Create a New User</wintitle> window opens. <fig
                        id="fig_create-new-user">
                        <image href="../_images/gui-screen-shots/users_create-new-user.jpg"
                            id="image_h44_ykn_jq" scale="70"/>
                    </fig></info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Enter the user information.</cmd>
                <choicetable id="choicetable_user-info" relcolwidth="1* 4*">
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Full Name</choption>
                        <chdesc>Mandatory. The user's full name.</chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>User name</choption>
                        <chdesc>Mandatory. The user ID for this user. The <wintitle>User
                                Name</wintitle> field autopopulates with the first initial and last
                            name entered for as the user's full name. For example, if the user's
                            full name is <keyword>Jane Smith</keyword>, the <wintitle>User
                                Name</wintitle> field autopopulates with <keyword>jsmith</keyword>.
                            The user ID can be edited after it has been autopopulated. IDs can be up
                            to 16 characters long. Alphabetic and numeric characters are permitted,
                            as well as underscore ("_")</chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Phone Number</choption>
                        <chdesc>Optional. The user's phone number. You must configure this field if
                            you want the system to send alerts to the user's phone. </chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Email</choption>
                        <chdesc>Mandatory. The user's email address. If you configure the system to
                            send email alerts to the user, this is the email address that will be
                            used.</chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Role</choption>
                        <chdesc>Mandatory. The user's system role. Together with the user
                            authorization configured and the visibility set for data, the user role
                            determines what access the user will have to data. A user can be
                            assigned more than one role. <xref href="con_user-roles.xml">Tell me
                                about user roles.</xref></chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Authorizations</choption>
                        <chdesc>Optional. The types of data the user is authorized to access. Use
                            either the <uicontrol>Shift</uicontrol> key or the
                                <uicontrol>Ctrl</uicontrol> key to make multiple selections. <xref
                                href="con_user-authorizations.xml">Tell me about user
                                authorizations.</xref></chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                    <chrow>
                        <choption>Password</choption>
                        <chdesc>Mandatory. Note that the password must comply with your
                            organization's password policy. <xref
                                href="../Passwords/con_password-policies.xml#concept_password-policies"
                                >Tell me about the password policy.</xref></chdesc>
                    </chrow>
                </choicetable>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Save the user information by clicking the <uicontrol>Save User</uicontrol>
                    button. The system confirms when the user has been successfully saved. Click
                        <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol> to close the screen.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
